

Applicant for:

Web Backend Developer (Java)~2000\$

Dr.JOY 25 February 2020

Vượng Đoàn

vuongnd74@gmail.com

Main interests: Java, Project Manager

What skills, work projects or achievements make you a strong candidate for this position?

More than 6 years experience: Java web, java core

- Work with web app, web service systems
- Work with under-processes that handle network business
- Other programming languages: Java script, Spark, XML, HTML, CSS, Shell script
- Work in projects which provide reports base on platform database, optimize SQL to increase system performance
- Database: Oracle, MySQL, Hadoop, HBase, Sybase
- Analysis, design system
- Be responsible as Project Technical Leader, PM
- Experience work with BigData: Hadoop, HBase



Nguyen Doan Vuong

Senior Java Developer, Technical Leader, Analysis and Design System Engineer, Project Manager

Date of birth: April 07, 1990

Gender: Male

Phone: 0989902763

Email: vuongnd74@gmail.com

Address: Kim No, Dong Anh, Hanoi, Vietnam

OBJECTIVE

Improving project management skills to manage bigger projects more effectively. Always study and practice to gain knowledge as well as experiences about software development major, to support/ resolve any technical/ process issues. Research new technology to apply to real projects, to make as good as possible qualify of software products. Keep studying is the way to reach higher level in career path as in life.

EDUCATION

Sep 2008 - Jul 2012	Hanoi University of Industry Major: Computer Science Graduation: Good degree
Jun 2005 - Jul 2005	Oracle Training Course Develope Web with JAX-WS & JAXRS Develope Web component with SERVLETS & JSPS

WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2018 - Present

World Fusion Vietnam

Solution Engineer, Technical Leader, Team Leader, PM $\,$

Java core

- Use java core to handle business statistics, synthesis and analysis
- Launch the data reports at branch and corporate level
- Other programming language: Shell script.

<u>Junit</u>

Use Junit 4 with Mockito and PowerMockito to test and simulate functionality, to perform Unit Test for system.

C#

Use C# for create UI and process in client side.

Oracle

Work in projects which provide reports base on platform database Oracle

Be responsible to:

- Analysis, design system
- Technical Leader

- Team Leader
- PM

Aug 2012 - April 2018

Viettel Software Center

Developer > Solution Engineer > Technical Leader > System Analysis and Design Engineer > Project Manager

More than 5 years experience:

Java web, java core

- Work with web app, web service systems
- Work with under-processes that handle network business
- Other programming languages: Java script, Spark, XML, HTML, CSS...

Oracle

- Work in projects which provide reports base on platform database Oracle, optimize SQL to increase system performance
- Database: Oracle, MySQL, Hadoop, HBase, Sybase

More than 4 years experience:

- Analysis, design system
- Be responsible as Project Technical Leader
- Be responsible as Project Manager

1 year experience:

Work with BigData: Hadoop, HBase

PROJECTS

Residential Management System in Japan

(May 2019 - Present)

Customer	Administrative authority
Description	 The system of managing all operations of Japanese administrative agencies such as residential management, taxation, housing, vehicle, health, welfare, immigration Management system, data storage and aggregation of data into reports. The system creates templates to serve the administrative operations of people. Connect with subsystems such as hospital management system, police station management system, pickup and lost management system
Team size	4
My position	PM, Technical Leader, Onsite in Osaka(Sep 2019 - Nov 2019)
My responsibilities	- Get requirement, analysis and design, provide solution - Development modules - Review code - Optimize code, SQL queries - Fix bugs - Manage process, risks, solution, issues - Summary of common codes can be used for many functions, help team members can refer to the code when needing to do the same features.
Technologies used	COKAS-R/ADII report, Java for Server, C# for Client, Oracle

Electric Power Management System in Japan

(Apr 2018 - Apr 2019)

Customer	Electric Power Corporation
Description	 The system manages, statistics, synthesizes, analyzes data of electricity branches and provides data distribution to partners as well as aggregating data for the electric power corporation. The data collection system of electric items such as transmission lines, underground lines, materials to be exported, used, returned then synthesized and managed on the system helps to optimize work, increase efficiency of management for electric power system.
Team size	6
My position	Technical Leader, Analysis and Design System Engineer
My responsibilities	- Get requirement, analysis and design, provide solution - Development modules - Review code - Optimize code, SQL queries - Fix bugs - Manage process, risks, solution, issues - Summary of common codes can be used for many functions,help team members can refer to the code when needing to do the same features Create tools to create test data, create automated code to increase productivity
Technologies used	Mybatis Framework, Oracle, Junit, Mockito, PowerMockito

SOCIT 2.0 (Service Operator Center IT) (Sep 2017 - Apr 2018)

Customer	Viettel Customer Service Center
Description	 Is an automated system for detecting and solving problems arising from business software in Viettel's software ecosystem. Is a system which collects logs of software transactions, defined errors arise and how to resolve. When one system error occurs, or reflects on Customer Service Center, CS staff customer care can lookup time of the error, the cause of the error, how to fix and can respond back to the customer, fix immediately to customers uninterrupted service. The system requires large data analysis to be applied BigData technology using Hadoop storage and Hbase for fast retrieval errors, avoiding long waiting customers when customer care staff check and process.
Team size	5
My position	Project Manager, Technical Leader, Analysis and Design System Engineer
My responsibilities	 Get requirement, analysis and design, provide solution Development modules Review code Optimize code, SQL queries Fix bugs Manage process, risks, solution, issues
Technologies used	Vaadin Framework, Primefaces Framework, Hibernate, Oracle, Web service SOAP, Java web, Java core, Hadoop, Hbase, kafka, scala, Java Script, HTML, CSS

SOCIT (Service Operator Center IT)

(Mar 2017 - Apr 2018)

Customer	Viettel Customer Service Center
	- Is an automated system for detecting and solving problems arising from business software in Viettel's software ecosystem.
Description	- Is a system which collects logs of software transactions, defined errors arise and how to resolve. When one system error occurs, or reflects on Customer Service Center, CS staff customer care can lookup time of the error, the cause of the error, how to fix and can respond back to the customer, fix immediately to customers

	uninterrupted service. The system requires large data analysis to be applied BigData technology using Hadoop storage and Hbase for fast retrieval errors, avoiding long waiting customers when customer care staff check and process.
Team size	5
My position	Project Manager, Technical Leader, Analysis and Design System Engineer
My responsibilities	 Get requirement, analysis and design, provide solution Development modules Review code Optimize code, SQL queries Fix bugs Manage process, risks, solution, issues
Technologies used	Vaadin Framework, Primefaces Framework, Hibernate, Oracle, Web service SOAP, Java web, Java core, Hadoop, Hbase, kafka, scala, Java Script, HTML, CSS

KPI CNTT

(Feb 2017 - Apr 2018)

Customer	Viettel Network Cooperation, Viettel Technical Department
Description	- Is a software quality assessment system based on user experiences. The system builds a Firefox add-on and installs on user devices. The add-on will send information about user activities to a centralized system. User activities's information such as which functions, at which IP, which system, when, the processing time of each action
	- Is a system collects large amount of logs from a variety of software systems, thus require processing large amount of data by BigData, Hadoop technology to store and process quickly, optimally, no need using too high server configuration system.
Team size	3
My position	Project Manager, Maintainer
My responsibilities	- Development new modules, and maintain existing modules - Review code - Optimize code, SQL queries - Fix bugs - Manage process, risks, solution, issues
Technologies used	Strut2 Framework, Hibernate, Oracle, Web service SOAP, Java web, Java core, Hadoop, Java Script, HTML, CSS

NPMS 1.0 (Network Performance Management System 1.0)

(Aug 2012 - Apr 2018)

Customer	Viettel Network Corporation, Viettel Telecom Corporation, 10 markets of Viettel (Laos, Cambodia, East Timor, Myanmar, Mozambique, Cameroon, Burundi, Tanzania, Haiti, Peru)
Description Team size	 Is a management and quality assessment system of Viettel network system Is a system of data collection from a wide variety types of telecommunication equipments, different partners Process a large amount of data quickly and accurately Providing monitoring, reporting, trend charts, network quality warnings of
	telecommunications equipment, of each district, province, region, country integrated on a unique system.
	17
My position	Project Manager, Technical Leader, Analysis and Design System Engineer, Developer
	- Get requirement, analysis and design, provide solution - Development modules

Technologies used	Strut2, Hibernate, Oracle, Web service SOAP, Java web, Java core, Java Script, HTML, CSS
My responsibilities	 Review code Optimize code, SQL queries Fix bugs Deploy to markets Manage process, risks, solution, issues

NPMS 2.0 (Network Performance Management System 2.0)

(Oct 2017 - Apr 2018)

Customer	Viettel Network Corporation, Viettel Telecom Corporation, 10 markets of Viettel (Laos, Cambodia, East Timor, Myanmar, Mozambique, Cameroon, Burundi, Tanzania, Haiti, Peru)
Description	 Upgrade version of the network management and assessment system of telecommunication network Viettel - NPMS Apply new technology to the system, reduce data delay time, bring more dynamic views to users (users are able to design report templates, charts, automatic analysis of data)
Team size	4
My position	Project Manager, Technical Leader, Analysis and Design System Engineer, Developer
My responsibilities	 Get requirement, analysis and design, provide solution Development modules Optimize code, SQL queries Fix bugs Deploy to markets Manage process, risks, solution, issues
Technologies used	Hadoop, Tableau, Oracle, Web service SOAP, Java core

OTHER SKILLS

Working	 Ability to capture and analyze new project requirements quickly Take the initiative to learn new technologies to apply to work Working skills, manage a working group Ability to work under high pressure Be a good listener, absorbing ideas, learn from experience optimistically Analytical skills, identification of risks, problems
Language	Able to read, write in English basically

INTERESTS

- Spend free time with family Soccer: Read sports news, take part in soccer activities
- Technology: Update technology information in the world in the field
 Mobile games: Action games, role-playing